

Moscow, Russia

# Sergey Kim

in/sergevkim sergevkim serge.kim

# SUMMARY

I am a fourth year Computer Science student with both research and development experience. My interests include, but are not limited to Computer Vision. Profound knowledge of Pure and Applied Mathematics allows me to study and work efficiently in different fields. I want to make the world a better place.

#### EXPERIENCE

WayRay ♂

Junior Research Engineer

Moscow, Russia 01/2021 - Present

 $egin{aligned} egin{aligned} egin{aligned\\ egin{aligned} egi$ 

- Working on auto camera calibration
- Working on lane detection

Samsung AI Center 🗗

Research Engineer Intern

Moscow, Russia 07/2020 - 03/2021

Python PyTorch3D Open3D

- Working on automatic labeling tool for indoor scene images
- Implemented methods to recover missing modalities: 3D semantics, 3D bounding boxes
- Compared some SLAM methods for the Scene Reconstruction on real data

Yandex Research

Moscow, Russia

Research Scientist Intern

06/2020 - 07/2020

Python PyTorch

- Observed walks in the GAN latent space
- Implemented a classifier for better variety of directions in the latent space

Yandex Technologies 🖸

Moscow, Russia 07/2019 - 11/2019

Software Engineer Intern

C++ Halide Python PyTorch

- Improved the main pipeline of camera app by adding learnable demosaicing layers
- Designed demosaicing layers as handcrafted PyTorch layers within Halide

## **EDUCATION**

#### HSE University

Moscow, Russia

BSc in Computer Science, Specialization in Machine Learning

09/2017 - 06/2021

- Advanced Group in Mathematics and Machine Learning
- Teaching Assistant in Machine Learning and Introduction to Machine Learning courses
- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning in Audio Processing, Generative Models, Bayesian Methods, Convex Optimization, Discrete Optimization, Computer Systems Architecture, DevOps

#### **PROJECTS**

# Audio Processing Solutions

2020

[Python][PyTorch]

- Implemented main sections of Audio Processing:
- Automatic Speech Recognition QuartzNet
- Text-to-Speech Synthesis Tacotron2 and WaveNet Vocoder
- Audio Enhancement CGAN and WaveNet

### Single Image Reflection Separation

2019 - 2020

Python PyTorch OpenCV

- Created an algorithm that detects and separates reflection from a single image
- Reproduced a physics-based way to synthesize data
- Final neural network architecture is U-Net with modifications

### Urban Scene Images Semantic Segmentation

2019

[Python] [TensorFlow] [Keras] [OpenCV]

- Implemented methods of semantic segmentation of urban scene images
- Reproduced and compared classical models: U-Net, Mask R-CNN, DeepLab

### Reinforcement Learning in Renju Game

2019

2016, 2017

Python | TensorFlow | Keras

- Created an algorithm that predicts the next move in renju
- Implemented two architectures: simple CNN classifier and Q-learning algorithm

# SKILLS

#### **Programming**

- **Proficient in:** Python, C++, C
- Familiar with: Bash, SQL, MATLAB, Halide

#### Machine Learning

- Proficient in: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, Open3D
- Familiar with: PyTorch3D, CatBoost, LightGBM, JAX

Moscow Olympiad in Mathematics, second degree diploma

#### **Technologies**

- Tools: Git, Docker, DVC, Spark, Hadoop, Terraform, CMake
- Other: Linux, Vim, LATEX, Blender

#### OTHER

O	uII	шеі	. 3	CH	υυ	12

• HSE University and Yandex Autumn School on Generative Models	2020
• Tsinghua University Deep Learning Summer School	2020
• Sirius University and Yandex Research School, Machine Learning	2019
<ul> <li>Sirius University and Tinkoff Project School, Analytics</li> </ul>	2019
• Sirius University and Yandex Project School, Machine Learning	2019
Competitions	
• Yandex Hackathon "HackTheRealty", top 4 of more than 50 teams	2020
• University Olympiad in Applied Mathematics and Informatics, second degree diploma	2020
• Moscow Olympiad in Informatics, second degree diploma	2017

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Gasnikov AV, Dvurechensky PE, Zhukovskii ME, Kim SV, Plaunov SS, Smirnov DA, Noskov FA. About the Power Law of the PageRank Vector Component Distribution. Part 2. The Buckley–Osthus Model, Verification of the Power Law for This Model, and Setup of Real Search Engines. Numerical Analysis and Applications. 2018 Jan 1;11(1):16-32.